<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>XiaochenCui&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://cuixiaochen.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on XiaochenCui&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 13:56:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cuixiaochen.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>System Research Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://cuixiaochen.com/posts/system-research-syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 13:56:32 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cuixiaochen.com/posts/system-research-syllabus/</guid>
      <description>The knowledge involved in building large-scale system, covering everthing form architecture to algorithms, from macro to micro.
Comments and suggestions are welcomed.
(Content is being sorted out, a little bit confusing right now)
☑︎ means read
⭐️ means recommend
Distributed Systems  Time, Clocks, and the Ordering of Events in a Distributed System The End of an Architectural Era (It’s Time for a Complete Rewrite) Practical Uses of Synchronized Clocks in Distributed Systems Information Storage in a Decentralized Computer System  Data Processing  Spark: Cluster Computing with Working Sets  Stream Processing  Storm @Twitter Samza: Stateful Scalable Stream Processing at LinkedIn Drill  SQL Workloads  Presto: SQL on Everything 深入浅出Presto：PB级OLAP引擎 Dremel: Interactive Analysis of Web-Scale Datasets  Distributed Storage System  Atlas: Baidu’s Key-value Storage System for Cloud Data PAST: Persistent and Anonymous Storage in a Peer-to-Peer Networking Environment OceanStore: An Architecture for Global-Scale Persistent Storage Alluxio: A Virtual Distributed File System  Distributed Computation  Ray: A Distributed Framework for Emerging AI Applications Starling: A Scalable Query Engine on Cloud Functions  Database Motivation  A Relational Model of Data for Large Shared Data Banks  History  ☑︎ What Goes Around Comes Around ☑︎ What’s Really New with NewSQL?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
